# Megan Rodgers



FASHION DESIGN

 $(330)\ 354-8647$ 

0

Canton, OH



www.meganrodgers.me



meganrodgers.me@gmail.com



# **EDUCATION**

#### **FASHION DESIGN**

Minor: Sustainability Kent State University 2017 - 2020

# SUSTAINABLE DESIGN ENTREPRENEUR

F.I.T - Continued Education 2016 - 2017

#### FASHION MERCHANDISING

Minor: Marketing Kent State University 2012 - 2016

# **SKILLS**

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE
MACHINE KNITTING
DIGITAL KNITTING
TEXTILE DESIGN
MS OFFICE
BLUECHERRY - PLM SYSTEM

#### **PROFILE**

My name is Megan Kodgers and I am currently studying at Kent State University for Fashion Design and have a bachelor's degree in Fashion Merchandising. I was chosen as one of the top 30 students in my Senior class to be shown in the annual Portfolio Showcase. With my education and experience, I would be an assest to your company in Assistant Designer position. As a Design Assistant at Ellery Homestyles, I was described as having an "insane work ethic". I demonstrated that I had an eye for design and could be trusted to finish the job.

## **EXPERIENCES**

#### DESIGN INTERN - SWEATER DEPARTMENT

Ann Taylor / New York, NY / June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Spearheaded the design of a capsule collection for a Ann Taylor Intern presentation to high-level executives at the end of the internship
- Collaborated with Ann Taylor interns to target new customers
- Created Fall 2020 techpacks for Sweater Creative Design team
- Assisted in fit meetings, sketch reviews and Spring '20 P.O.V review
- Organized the Spring and Fall 2020 concept and line boards for sweater design team

### DESIGN ASSISTANT - WINDOW/BLANKET

Ellery Homestyles / New York, NY / Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- Created techpacks for all Window and Blanket production samples on the PLM system BlueCherry
- Worked alongside Window Design team while designing upcoming market doing trend, color and fabric reserach, attending tradeshows and trend presentations
- Oversaw communication with overseas production team and requested production samples, matches lab-dips and approved strike-off samples to ensure desired production quality

#### **DESIGN INTERN - BEDDING DEPARTMENT**

Ellery Homestyles / New York, NY / June 2015 - Aug. 2015

- Assembled presentation boards and pulled fabric samples for buyer meetings
- Created and prepared engravings, mappings and pre-techs for Waverly, VUE, Historic Charleston, Belk and Blissliving collections to send overseas for production
- Controlled the design and production of nine pillows for the Jilo bedding collection for Belk